Nasir Firdaush

Front End Developer

My Contact

- ☐ nasirkhan000k@gmail.com
- +918405842008
- Okhla South Delhi 110025

Skills

- JavaScript
- · React.js
- Redux.js
- jQuery
- Git
- Bootstrap
- HTML5
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Education Background

- Galgotias University
 Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science
 Completed in 2016
- Larana Business School
 Intermediate of science(I. SC)

 Completed in 2017
- Satyam International School Matriculation

Completed in 2015

Website & Portfolio Links

- **LINKEDIN**
- **PORTFOLIO**

About Me

Skilled Developer with 1.6 years of experience in developing and implementing front-end architectures that have resulted in significant increases in page load speed and user engagement. Proficient in collaborating with back-end teams to integrate userfacing elements with server-side logic, implementing automated testing platforms, and optimizing components for maximum performance. staying upto-date with emerging technologies and frameworks, and reducing development time for new projects

Professional Experience

McCoy Mart | HTML Developer

May 2023 - Present (9 months)

- Designed and developed a new user interface for a web application
- Developed innovative JavaScript web technologies to build a user-friendly, adaptive, and responsive website with improved cross-browser compatibility and optimized runtime performance
- Stayed up-to-date on emerging technologies and implemented new features, resulting in increase in website functionality and improved user experience.

Abaris Softech | Frontend Developer

Mar 2022 - May 2023 (1 yr 3 months)

- Designed and developed a reusable component library for future use, resulting in reduction in development time for new projects.
- Utilized Redux for state management, resulting in reduction in code complexity and increase in team productivity.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to integrate user-facing elements with server-side logic, resulting in a reduction in page load times and improved website performance.

Web2byte | Summer Intern

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021 (4 months)

- Developed and implemented a responsive design for a company website.
- Enhanced the usability of existing applications by applying the latest accessibility standards and best practices
- Collaborated with project managers to successfully deliver projects on time, resulting in an increase in organizational efficiency